<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research blog</title>
    <link>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Research blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:03:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Meta Learning</title>
      <link>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/post/meta-learning-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:03:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/post/meta-learning-start/</guid>
      <description>Meta-learning is one of the hottest topics of research. In recent years, many researchers have taken interested in meta-learning due to its promise to reach generalization. In this blog post, we present a brief introduction to concepts in meta-learning and some applications which will immerse you in this wonderful field.&#xA;An starting point of view One can notice that humans or animals can learn a task quickly when they have prior knowledge on another similar task.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cadena de Markov (MC)</title>
      <link>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/post/markov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 20:13:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/post/markov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La segunda acepción de la &lt;a href=&#34;https://dle.rae.es/secuencia?m=form&#34;&gt;RAE&lt;/a&gt; nos dice que una &lt;strong&gt;secuencia&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;es una sucesión de cosas que guardan entre sí cierta relación&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. En el mundo real podemos encontrar innumerables ejemplos que se ajustan a esta definición. Por ejemplo, en aplicaciónes de transformación de audio a texto y visceverza, pronóstico del clima, en el control de robots o procesamiento de video, etc. En ese sentido, es importante poder abstraer modelos matemáticos que nos permitan estudiar mejor estos procesos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Model Based Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/post/ambrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 15:39:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/post/ambrl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reinforcement learning is a very interesting research topic, in recent years, their applications and their performance have been growing quickly. In this blog post, we present the basics of model-based reinforcement learning and its recent advances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericktornero.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello!, This is Erick. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m pursuing a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science, at Universidad Católica San Pablo, Arequipa-Perú. I am so interested in how to solve complex tasks in robotics through reinforcement learning.&#xA;Find more information about me in erick-tornero-portfolio. If you have any questions or want to keep in touch, feel free to mail me to erick.tornero@ucsp.edu.pe</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
